Contact

louisewhite@msn.com

www.linkedin.com/in/louise-white-63644255 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Executive Management Strategic Planning Healthcare Industry

Louise White

CNO/VP Patient Care Services, Sharp Grossmont Hospital Greater San Diego Area

Summary

Strategic healthcare leader with over 20 years experience encompassing healthcare system and hospital operations, patient care services delivery, nursing care, facility expansion projects, EMR installations, physician alignment, service line and intsitute development and marketing, startegic planning for integrated healthcare systems, and executive leadership of a pediatric and adult medical centers.

Experience

Sharp Grossmont Medical Center Chief Nursing officer and Vice President patient Care Services October 2014 - Present (5 years 10 months)

La Mesa San Diego

CHOC Children's Hospital of Orange County
Vice President Patient Care Services and Chief Nursing Officer
November 2011 - May 2014 (2 years 7 months)

accomplishments:

- Orchestrated the completion and very successful operationalization of a new 250,000-square-foot pediatric hospital, including surgical services, emergency room, endoscopy, heart Institute, inpatient units, radiology and laboratory services. On boarded 600 new employees and passed licensure and JCAHO accreditation.
- 2. Achieved Magnet re-designation and Beacon award for PICU
- 3. Improved pharmaceutical stewardship resulting in \$4 million in expense reduction.
- 4. Initiated a 340b plan for pharmaceuticals, resulting in \$2 million annual cost reduction
- 5. Opened two NICU satellite locations improving alliances with adult hospitals and increasing CHOC NICU volume by 2%.
- 6. Led the successful implementation of Cerner IT system in new hospital services.

7. Institute development and operations

Eisenhower Medical Center

Vice President health care services and Chief Nursing Officer September 2002 - November 2011 (9 years 3 months)

Rancho mirage California

accomplishments:

- Completed a new 200,000-square-foot, 200-bed telemetry and ICU pavilion,
 24-bed VIP unit, 44-bed emergency department. Developed an integrated
 Heart and Vascular Hospital within a hospital, and an orthopedic hospital.
- 2. Facilitated the successful implementation of a complete McKesson system electronic medical record (EMR) within two years.
- 3. Implemented extensive Recruitment and Retention Program, resulting in the hiring of 350 Registered Nurses in two years and reducing open RN positions to 17.
- 4. Reduced contract labor costs from \$13 million (172,080 hours) to \$3 million (7,756 hours).
- 5. Over a three-year period, patient satisfaction scores rose from 17th percentile to the 85th by Press Ganey measurement.

Louise White and Associates President and CEO 2002 - 2004 (2 years)

California

Louise White & Associates, Rancho Mirage. California

Offered consultative services for a broad spectrum of health care projects and challenges including strategic planning, construction development, leadership training, regulatory compliance, accountable care organization development, and staff development.

- # Completed business plan, and pro-forma for USC heart hospital.
- # Consulted on the architectural design and space planning of the new USC heart hospital.
- # Advised Medtronic on multiple educational needs and price contracting.
- # Served a member of the Medtronic's international business advisory board.
- # Consulted with the 29 Palms Marine base on future health care construction needs.
- # Provided clinical educational needs to multiple health care organizations in Southern California.
- # Participated on the McKesson Advisory Board for clinical IT development.

Provided leadership and management training to hospitals, board of directors, and universities.

Lectured on International health care systems to faculty at Oxford University, England.

MemorialCare Health System Vice President Heart Institute March 1994 - September 2002 (8 years 7 months) Long Beach California

Lakewood Regional Medical Center Director Cardiac Surgery 1989 - 1992 (3 years)

Heart Institute of the Desert Cardiovsacular Nurse specialist surgery/cath lab/ clinics 1984 - 1989 (5 years) Rancho Mirage California

Education

North Lothian school of nursing and midwifery Nursing degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse

University of Phoenix
Bachelors, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse

University of Phoenix
Masters, Health/Health Care Administration/Management